Finding Aid for the Ralph Greenson Papers LSC.1497
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Lectures & broadcasts by RRG [large reels]
  - Conflict between religion and psychoanalysis, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - People who hate (Tape 1 of 2), 1960 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    Taped 12 Feb., broadcast 26 Mar. KPFK broadcast. 1 reel.
  - People who hate (Tape 2 of 2), 1960 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Sleep, dreams & death (Tape 1 of 3), 1961 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Sleep, dreams & death (Tape 2 of 3), 1961 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Sleep, dreams & death (Tape 3 of 3), 1961 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Sleep, dreams & death, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    School for Nursery Years lecture series. 1 reel.
  - Laughter & tears, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    26 June. KPFK broadcast. 1 reel.
  - That impossible profession - plenary speech, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    APA. 1 reel.
  - Freud's death as it was experienced in Los Angeles, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    Hacker Clinic. 1 reel. Also talks by Rudolph Ekstein, Martin Grotjohn, Frederick Hacker.
  - I - Sex without passion, II - Decline of love & passion today, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    1 reel. Side 1 - 3/13/66. Side II - 3/24/66.
  - Decline of love & passion today, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    1 reel. Reiss - Davis Child Study Center, 13 June.
  - Transvestism in a young boy - RRG & Robert Stoller, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    1 reel. UCLA?
  - Fascination of violence, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    1 reel. Claremont College, 19 February.
  - Sex without passion, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    1 reel. Address at Reiss - Davis Child Study Center (Women's Division), 30 April.
  - Studies in violence 1 & 2, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    1 reel. UCLA.
  - Studies in violence 3 & 4, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Studies in violence 5, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Studies in violence 6, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    1 reel. UCLA
  - Studies in violence 7 & 8, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Hate in the happy family, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    1 reel. Reiss - Davis Child Study Center (Women's Division), 28 April.
  - RRG confronts women's lib, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    1 reel. Reiss - Davis Child Study Center (Women's Division), 26 April.
  - Jealousy, envy & possessiveness, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    1 reel. Reiss - Davis Child Study Center (Women's Division), 7 February.
  - Crisis of adult life, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    1 reel. Reiss - Davis Child Study Center (Women's Division), 20 February.
  - Boredom American style, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    1 reel. Reiss - Davis Child Study Center (Women's Division), 21 April.
  - The devil made me do it, Dr. Freud, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    1 reel. Leo Beck Temple.
  - Anna Freud, the nature of the therapeutic process, no date (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Lectures & broadcasts by RRG [small reels]
  - Emotional involvement, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    1 reel. Reiss - David Child Study Center. 1 of 2.
  - Clinical varieties of sexual apathy, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    1 reel. AMA, Las Vegas, 30 November. 1 of 2.
  - Parenthood in the 60ties & CEE dedication ceremony, 1967 & 1968 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    1 reel. CEE, 4 November & 26 May.
  - Changing patterns in love and sex, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    1 reel. Reiss - Davis Child Study Center, 18 October.
  - Fascination with violence, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Sophie Portnoy answers back, no date (Box 12, Folder 9)
    1 reel. Reiss - Davis Child Study Center.
  - Sex without passion, no date (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Hate in the happy family, no date (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Schizophrenia #1, no date (Box 12, Folder 12)
    1 reel. Los Angeles, 19 June.
  - Schizophrenia #2, no date (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Transference: Freud or Klein, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    1 reel. 20 September.
  - Clinical varieties of sexual apathy, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    1 reel. AMA, Los Vegas, 30 November. 2 of 2.
  - Emotional involvement, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    1 reel. Reiss - Davis Child Study Center. 2 of 2.
  - Sessions #1 - 4, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    1 reel. UCLA. 12, 19 & 26 September, 3 October.
  - Sessions #5 - 8, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    1 reel. UCLA. 10 & 17 October, 7 & 14 November.
  - Sessions #9 - 12, 1967 - 1968 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    1 reel. UCLA. 5, 19 & 26 December, 23 January.
  - Sessions #13 - 16, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    1 reel. UCLA. 20 & 27 February, 5 & 19 March.
  - Tape #5, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    1 reel. UCLA. 26 March, 9 April, 21 May & 4 June.
- Lectures, patient notes, etc.
  - Notes for lecture - 1972, caricature of RRG - 1971, note from patient, and programs, 1971 - 1972 (Box 32, Folder 8)
- Marilyn Monroe
  - Books about Marilyn Monroe (box 1 of 2) (Box 34)
  - Books about Marilyn Monroe (box 2 of 2) (Box 35)
  - Clippings & articles re Marilyn Monroe (Box 36)
  - Letters to MM from various persons and MM letters to RRG, 1960 - 1961, no date (Box 39, Folder 1)
    Box 39, folder 1 is closed until January 1, 2039.
  - MM - pre 1962, 1958 - 1962 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    Box 39, folder 2 is closed until January 1, 2039.
  - MM - post 1962, 1962 - 1973 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    Box 39, folder 3 is closed until January 1, 2039.
  - Joan Greenson manuscript re MM - photocopy, no date (Box 39, Folder 4)
    Box 39, folder 4 is closed until January 1, 2039.
  - MM legal, 1962 - 1966 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    Box 39, folder 5 is closed until January 1, 2039.
  - MM's death and crank mail, 1962 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    Box 39, folder 6 is closed until January 1, 2039.
  - Medical Tribune article - re confidentiality, 1975 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    Box 39, folder 7 is closed until January 1, 2039.
  - Reviews of books about MM (Box 39, Folder 8)
    Box 39, folder 8 is closed until January 1, 2039.
  - Letters re published material (Box 39, Folder 9)
    Box 39, folder 9 is closed until January 1, 2039.
  - Der Blick suit, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    Box 39, folder 10 is closed until January 1, 2039.
  - Interview re MM - Maurice Zolotow, 1973 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    Box 39, folder 11 is closed until January 1, 2039.
  - Condolences to RRG and RRG letters to Marianne Kris, 1961 - 1962 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    Box 39, folder 12 is closed until January 1, 2039.
- Medical aspects of human sexuality
  - Clippings & articles - questions & answers - short monographs, 1968 - 1976 (Box 30, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous papers, notes, articles
  - What do we know about jealousy? - draft - appeared in Look Magazine[issue is in Box 38], 1955 (Box 29, Folder 22)
    August.
  - Psychoanalysis & propaganda, 1942 (Box 29, Folder 23)
    13 Mar. Psychoanalytic Study Group, Los Angeles.
  - Recent developments in psychoanalysis - extensive typed notes, 1949 (Box 29, Folder 24)
  - Freudian psychoanalysis, 1950 (Box 29, Folder 25)
    21 Feb. Presented at UCLA Round Table.
  - On the beginning of speech & language - 2 versions & typed notes, 1950 (Box 29, Folder 26)
    5 May.
  - Introduction to [forum?] audience of Karl Menninger, 1951 (Box 29, Folder 27)
    10 Jan.
  - Remarks on the care & maintenance of the adult person, 1954 (Box 29, Folder 28)
  - The psychoanalyst looks at the family physician, 1956 (Box 29, Folder 29)
    Nov. Third annual Institute for Physicians, Reiss Davis Clinic.
  - Practical psychiatric advice for the general practitioner, 1957 (Box 29, Folder 30)
    Jan. Southern California Psychiatric Society.
  - Book review: Life & Work of Sigmund Freud, Vol. I by Ernest Jones, no date (Box 29, Folder 31)
  - Notes on "as-if" disorders, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 32)
    Dec.
  - The transitional object relationship: twinship - outline note, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 33)
    17 June.
  - Clinical note re slip of the tongue, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 34)
    2 May.
  - Memorandum: When childhood fantasies come true (note to Wexler), 1968 (Box 29, Folder 35)
    10 May.
  - NIMH Workshop: Panel on schizophrenia, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 36)
    15 Sept. Participants: Goldberg, Greenson, Grotstein, Malin & Wexler.
  - The feeling of the psychotherapist toward the patient, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 37)
    5 June. Commencement address?
  - In praise of Rocco Motto - 25th anniversary of Reiss Davis, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 38)
    18 June.
  - Remarks on the changing use of dreams, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 39)
    "Read at Intl. Congress by M. Khan after his paper."
  - The Monday hour, no date (Box 29, Folder 40)
    Topic included in Vol. I of Technique?
  - For Psychoanalytic Forum: A review, no date (Box 29, Folder 41)
  - A psychoanalyst's indictment of "The exorcist" - for Saturday Review, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    June.
  - Letters re Saturday Review article, no date (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - A psychoanalytic consultation, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    24 March.
  - Clinical note, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Clinical interview, no date (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Observation about grandchildren, David & Jessica, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    2 July.
- Otto Fenichel
  - Round letters, 1935 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Dialectics & psychoanalysis (German), 1934 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Theoretical implications of didactic analysis, no date (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Problems of psychoanalytic technique - translated by Davis Brunswick, no date (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Ueber die Gegenwartigen Richtungen innerhalb der Psychoanalyse [by Otto Fenichel], 1934 (Box 30, Folder 16)
    50 p. Oslo. Gift of Hanna Fenichel to RRG.
  - Psychoanalysis & the social sciences by Otto Fenichel, no date (Box 30, Folder 17)
    26 p. Gift of Hanna Fenichel to RRG.
  - [Untitled paper by Otto Fenichel, Prague], 1934 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    29 April. 26 p. Gift of Hanna Fenichel to RRG.
  - Zur Psychoanalyse der Prostitution [by Otto Fenichel], no date (Box 30, Folder 19)
    8 p. Prague. Gift of Hanna Fenichel to RRG.
  - Letters to RRG, 1944 - 1945 (Box 30, Folder 20)
    2 Feb. 1944 - 2 Dec. 1945. Gift of Hanna Fenichel to RRG.
  - Photos - Otto Fenichel & family, no date (Box 30, Folder 21)
- Panels - discussions - symposiums
  - Some clinical and theoretical considerations in acting out and impulse disorders, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - On acting out & impulse disorders, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Acting Out - Staff conference VA hospital, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Round table of sleep disorders - San Francisco, 1940, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - UCLA symposium Studies in violence - RRG chair, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence re arrangements for participants in Studies in Violence Symposium, 1967 - 1968 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - This question of violence - NET journal interview - transcript, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Free association - panel papers, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Female sexuality - panel paper, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - The first sexual experience of an adolescent boy and older woman, Oedipal triumph or tragedy? - paper by Kleinmann, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Transference interpretation, only? - panel paper and working papers, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Patient sessions - UCLA videotape transcripts
  - Tape 1, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    12 Sept.
  - Tape 2, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    19 Sept.
  - Tape 3, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    26 Sept.
  - Tape 4, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    3 Oct.
  - Tape 5, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    10 Oct.
  - Tape 6, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    17 Oct.
  - Tape 7, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    7 Nov.
  - Tape 8, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    14 Nov.
  - Tape 9, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    5 Dec.
  - Tape 10, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    19 Dec.
  - Tape 11, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    26 Dec.
  - Tape 12, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    23 Jan.
  - Tape 13, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    20 Feb.
  - Tape 14, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    27 Feb.
  - Tape 15, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    5 Mar.
  - Tape 16, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    19 Mar.
  - Tape 17, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    26 Mar.
  - Tape 18, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    9 Apr.
  - Tape 19, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    21 May.
  - Tape 20, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    4 June.
  - Tape 21, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 21)
- Private practice
  - Office inventory & income sheet, 436 N. Roxbury, B.H., 1949 (Box 32, Folder 5)
- Professional organizations
  - San Francisco Psychoanalytic Society - programs, 1940, 1942, 1943 (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - Almanach der Psychoanalyse, 1927 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Almanach der Psychoanalyse, 1928 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Almanach der Psychoanalyse, 1929 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Almanach der Psychoanalyse, 1930 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Almanach der Psychoanalyse, 1931 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Almanach der Psychoanalyse, 1932 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Psa - Info, no. 24, 1985 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    July.
  - Psa Institute & Society - meeting programs - Los Angeles & San Francisco, 1946 - 1977 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Programs - special, 1942 - 1977 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Programs - Public lectures - mental health, 1960 - 1977 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Programs - Annual meetings of American & Int'l Psa, KPFK & KPFA listing of talks (folder 1 of 2), 1961 - 1976 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Programs - Annual meetings of American & Int'l Psa, KPFK & KPFA listing of talks (folder 2 of 2), 1961 - 1976 (Box 32, Folder 1)
- Psychoanalytic associations & institute
  - Obituaries (Box Unknown container 210 for instance of Obituaries, Folder unknown container)
    Noted as missing on check-in list.
- Psychoanalytic associations and institutes
  - American Psychoanalytic Association Mid-winter meeting, NY - report on papers given, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - American Psychoanalytic Asso. Board of Professional Standards - Mimeographed program & agenda, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - 18th International Congress, London - report, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - 20th International Congress, Paris - report, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - APA May meeting, San Francisco - report, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - APA meeting, Beverly Hills - report, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - LAPSI Educational Committee - minutes, letters and agendas, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - LAPSI Admissions Committee - interviews, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Fenichel-Simmel lectures - committee memos and letters, 1964 - 1965 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Fenichel-Simmel lectures - The paranoid betrayal conflict, 1964 - 1965 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Memo from Otto Sperling to the APA re loyalty oath at UC Berkeley, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Committee on UC Loyalty Oath - memo to LAPS, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Manual for psychoanalytic candidates LA Institute, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Interview with RRG - By the Committee for the History of Society, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Psychoanalytic process [cassettes]
  - [1 of 18], 1972 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    2 February.
  - [2 of 18], 1972 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    9 February.
  - [3 of 18], 1972 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    16 February.
  - [4 of 18], 1972 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    23 February.
  - [5 of 18], 1972 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    1 March.
  - [6 of 18], 1972 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    8 March.
  - [7 of 18], 1972 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    15 March.
  - [8 of 18], 1972 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    22 March.
  - [9 of 18], 1972 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    29 March.
  - [10 of 18], 1972 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    5 April.
  - [11 of 18], 1972 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    19 April.
  - [12 of 18], 1972 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - [13 of 18], 1972 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    17 May.
  - [14 of 18], 1972 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    24 May.
  - [15 of 18], 1972 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    31 May.
  - [16 of 18], 1972 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    7 June.
  - [17 of 18], 1972 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    14 June.
  - [18 of 18] - Name of seminar participants, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    21 June.
- Public lectures
  - Working papers for lecture, UCLA, 1975 (Box Unknown container 211 for instance of Working papers for lecture, UCLA, Folder unknown container)
  - Apathy, boredom & miltown, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    School for Nursery Years.
  - Beyond sexual satisfaction, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    UC San Diego Extension Division & Hanna Fenichel Nursery School. 3 copies.
  - Boredom, American style, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Reiss - Davis Child Study Center. 4 copies.
  - Crisis in adult life, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Reiss - Davis Child Study Center. 2 copies.
  - Conflict between psychoanalysis & religion, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    School for Nursery Years. 2 copies.
  - Decline of love & passion today, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Annual meeting, Reiss - Davis Child Study Center. 2 copies.
  - The dread & love of death, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    UCLA Extension Division: Violent Death. 2 copies.
  - Emotional involvement, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    School for Nursery Years. KPFK-L.A., WBAI N.Y. & KPFA-Berkeley. 3 copies.
  - The fascination of violence, 1968 - 1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    UCLA Extension symposium (1968). Claremont College (1969). Studies in Violence. 2 copies.
  - Hate in the happy family, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Reiss - Davis Child Study Center. 3 copies.
  - Jealousy, envy & possessiveness, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Laughter and tears, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    1 copy.
  - Masculinity & femininity reconsidered, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Southern California Psychiatric Association. 3 copies and 2 letters.
  - Misunderstandings of psychoanalysis, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    1 copy and 4 abstracts.
  - People in search of a family, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    San Diego Psychiatric Institute. 2 copies.
  - People who hate, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    School for Nursery Years. KPFA-Berkeley. 2 copies.
  - Sex without passion, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    UCLA symposium: Age of boredom. San Francisco UC School of Medicine panel. 1 copy.
  - Sleep, dreams & death, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    School for Nursery Years. KPFK-Los Angeles & KPFA-Berkeley. 2 copies.
  - Sophie Portnoy answers back, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Founders dinner. Center for Early Education. 2 copies.
  - The devil made me do it, Dr. Freud, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Leo Baeck Temple: Series on Aggression. 2 copies.
  - Varieties of love, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    School for Nursery Years, KPFA-Berkeley. 2 copies.
  - Woman's Lib: A MCP Freudian psychoanalyst confronts women's lib, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Reiss Davis Child Study Center. 2 copies.
  - Why men like war, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    2 lectures - School for Nursery Years, KPFK-LA. 2 copies.
  - Why people hate psychoanalysis, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    UC San Diego. 2 copies.
  - You only live twice, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Introduction and table of contents to "The Greenson Public Lectures" by Hildi Greenson, no date (Box 2, Folder 10)
    UCLA - NPI.
- Publication of books
  - Technique & practice in psychoanalysis - correspondence with Lottie Newman, 1961 - 1967 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Technique & practice in psychoanalysis - reviews, no date (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Technique & practice in psychoanalysis - letters from colleagues, no date (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Technique & practice in psychoanalysis - Correspondence re publication, no date (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Explorations in psychoanalysis - correspondence with Lottie Newman and International Universities Press (folder 1 of 2), no date (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Explorations in psychoanalysis - correspondence with Lottie Newman and International Universities Press (folder 2 of 2), no date (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Explorations in psychoanalysis - reviews, no date (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Published articles
  - Letters received about sexual apathy paper, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and clippings re sexual apathy, 1966 - 1968 (Box 37, Folder 2)
- Published articles by RRG
  - Clippings & magazines (Box 37)
  - Clippings & magazines (Box 37)
  - Clippings & magazines (Box 38)
- Published papers
  - A case of agoraphobia, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Psychoanalytic Review.
  - Die Tecknik der Individual Psychologie Alfred Adler, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Munich.
  - Ein Fall von Platzangst, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Psychotherapeutische Praxis.
  - A famous case of compulsion, no date (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Psychoanalytic Review. Typescript.
  - On genuine epilepsy, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Psychoanalytic Quarterly. 2 copies.
  - Practical approach to war neuroses, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Bulletin Menninger Clinic. 2 copies.
  - On gambling, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Yearbook of Psychoanalysis. 3 copies.
  - The psychology of apathy, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Psychoanalytic Quarterly. 3 copies.
  - The mother tongue & the mother, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    IJP, Yearbook of Psychoanalysis. 3 copies.
  - On boredom, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Journal of the American Psychiatric Asso. 2 copies.
  - On moods & introjects, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Bulletin - Menninger Clinic. 2 copies.
  - About the sound mm, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - The struggle against identification, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Journal of the American Psychiatric Asso. 1 typescript (carbon) & 2 copies.
  - Forepleasure: its use for defensive purposes, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - On screen defenses, screen hunger & screen identity, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Journal of the American Psychiatric Asso. 1 ts(c) & 2 copies.
  - Psychiatric information for general practice, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    California Medicine. 3 copies.
  - Variations in classical psychoanalytic technique, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Intl. Journal of Psycho-Analysis. 3 copies.
  - The classic psychoanalytic approach, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Chapter 69, American Handbook of Psychiatry. 2 copies.
  - Phobia, anxiety & depression, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Journal of the American Psychiatric Asso. 1 typescript & 2 copies.
  - Empathy & its vicissitudes, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    International Journal of Psycho-Analysis. 1 ts & 2 copies.
  - Empathy, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Typescript.
  - Empathy & counter - transference, no date (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Ts.
  - On empathy & intuition, no date (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Ts(c).
  - Empathy & sublimation, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - On the silence & sounds of the analytic hour, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    Journal of American Psychiatric Asso. Ts(c) & 1 copy.
  - The selection of candidates for psychoanalytic training, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    Panel report. Journal of the American Psychiatric Asso. 3 copies.
  - On enthusiasm, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    Journal of the American Psychiatric Asso. 3 copies.
  - Therapeutic and working alliance, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    2 copies.
  - On homosexuality & gender identity, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Int'l Journal of Psycho-Analysis. 2 copies.
  - The working alliance & the transference neurosis, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - The problem of working through, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - That "impossible" profession, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - A transvestite boy and a hypothesis, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Int'l Journal of Psycho-Analysis. 1 ts(c) & 3 copies.
  - The enigma of modern woman, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Bulletin of the Philadelphia Asso. for Psycho-analysis. 1 ts(c) & 2 copies.
  - Otto Fenichel 1898 - 1946, no date (Box 4, Folder 8)
    The Encyclopedia of Psychoanalysis. 2 copies.
  - Masculinity & femininity in our time, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Reprint: Sexual problems in medical practice, edited by Charles W. Wahl. 3 copies.
  - The clinical use of the dream early in analysis, 1968, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Published first in Explorations in Psychoanalysis.
  - The use of dream sequences for detecting errors of technique: a clinical study, 1968, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Revision 1977.
  - On sexual apathy in the male, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    California Medicine. 1 ts & 3 copies.
  - Dis-identifying from mother: its special importance for the boy, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Intl. Journal of Psycho-analysis. 3 copies.
  - The origin & fate of new ideas in psychoanalysis, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Intl. Journal for Psycho-analysis. 3 copies.
  - The non-transference relationship in the psychoanalytic situation, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 15)